<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Music on don&#39;t panic</title>
    <link>https://qu-bit1.github.io/tags/music/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Music on don&#39;t panic</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2025 05:05:34 +0530</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://qu-bit1.github.io/tags/music/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>The Third Joke</title>
      <link>https://qu-bit1.github.io/posts/the-third-joke/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2025 05:05:34 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://qu-bit1.github.io/posts/the-third-joke/</guid>
      <description>&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;recommendations&#34;&gt;recommendations:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;music - been diving into some indian jazz like &lt;a href=&#34;https://music.apple.com/in/album/kolkata-stories/1596533984&#34;&gt;Kolkata stories&lt;/a&gt; by Bishu Chattopadhyay. the strokes(the whole including the voidz, julian singles), daft punk too and ofc not forgetting to consume my daily rap intake.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;books - not reading much lately but De Profundis, Projections and Hyperion are totally on my to read list which i&amp;rsquo;m going to finish this month.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While I’m not quite over the whole ‘meow zedong’ meme craze and instagram warning everyone that my account is compromised and I am a scammer in disguise(something to ponder upon), here I am again—banging on my keyboard just because the clackety-clack is oddly satisfying while I wait for Conda to finish installing in the background. So, yeah, the birthday was lit. winters? Even better. Got to visit six different states and, of course, drink unlimited beer. InterIIT? didn’t quite go as expected, but I’m still proud of the whole contingent, especially my kids. it was fun. frustrating at times, sure, but totally worth it. Maybe I should write another blog entirely about that trip and vacation. Could be fun.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <content>&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;recommendations&#34;&gt;recommendations:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;music - been diving into some indian jazz like &lt;a href=&#34;https://music.apple.com/in/album/kolkata-stories/1596533984&#34;&gt;Kolkata stories&lt;/a&gt; by Bishu Chattopadhyay. the strokes(the whole including the voidz, julian singles), daft punk too and ofc not forgetting to consume my daily rap intake.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;books - not reading much lately but De Profundis, Projections and Hyperion are totally on my to read list which i&amp;rsquo;m going to finish this month.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While I’m not quite over the whole ‘meow zedong’ meme craze and instagram warning everyone that my account is compromised and I am a scammer in disguise(something to ponder upon), here I am again—banging on my keyboard just because the clackety-clack is oddly satisfying while I wait for Conda to finish installing in the background. So, yeah, the birthday was lit. winters? Even better. Got to visit six different states and, of course, drink unlimited beer. InterIIT? didn’t quite go as expected, but I’m still proud of the whole contingent, especially my kids. it was fun. frustrating at times, sure, but totally worth it. Maybe I should write another blog entirely about that trip and vacation. Could be fun.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;joke&#34;&gt;joke&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lately, I’ve been on a bit of a music nostalgia trip—revisiting that early Chainsmokers pop era when life was simpler. Also, I finally shifted from Spotify to Apple Music. Why? Because why not. Gotta milk that hyped-up lossless spatial audio, which isn&amp;rsquo;t even compatible with most of the apple&amp;rsquo;s airpods or whatever their big chunky headphones are called, on my Sony WH-CH720N (pronounced &lt;em&gt;waahchh720n&lt;/em&gt;, obviously) which doesn’t exactly scream ‘Apple ecosystem.’ Tried it with and without a DAC cause why not spend those Gandhi&amp;rsquo;s if i cannot bet them on a bunch of racing ostriches because betting on dies is shady, there&amp;rsquo;s a probability factor and im just a simple biology student. but anyways i couldn&amp;rsquo;t experience the ultimate lossless audio which apple promised me but nvm got apple tv with it so it&amp;rsquo;s nice. that&amp;rsquo;s what a fool will think, apple music(called derek moving forward) have a really nice android app but it doesn&amp;rsquo;t have a proper sync feature so i can&amp;rsquo;t shift from phone to laptop to my explosive coffee maker, doesn&amp;rsquo;t have a proper mac app which is really ironic as apple software bad on apple hardware and good on android, caches locally on all the devices.
But ok some would shift back to spotify or deezer ffs, but no my autistic ass would go straight to derek&amp;rsquo;s developer documentation cause there exists one (surprised), would scan all the functionalities, design an architecture to solve most of my problems like make playlists from songs history(derek&amp;rsquo;s recommendations are really really nice), shift from one device to other and other stuff that tickles my OCD and urge to go back to my ex(spotify ofc). as fate would want i am Lencho in this story, Turns out, you need a $100 annual developer account. Classic Apple. That’s probably why no perfect third-party app exists for Mac. Well, maybe it&amp;rsquo;s better left untouched—history taught us how communism turned out.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;bonus---show-time&#34;&gt;Bonus - Show time&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the side note i got to try some of the apple tv shows out of which one really strikes out to me and which is ofc &amp;lsquo;The snoopy show&amp;rsquo;, no one can beat my snoopy in any way bro got the aura we all die for.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://qu-bit1.github.io/Shrinking.webp&#34; alt=&#34;shrinking&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On a serious note &amp;lsquo;Shrinking&amp;rsquo; is the one which i loved. now let me tell you first hand: no it&amp;rsquo;s not my trauma, mental health issues(i&amp;rsquo;ve got none hehe) or wanting to be acknowledged by my parents these are all the issues that got portrayed in this show. This time, I’m praising the writing, direction, score, and—of course—the cinematography. The story revolves around our fav. marshall eriksen(named jimmy in the show), his daughter, han solo(yipeeee) and their friends and neighbours with a special appearance of robin(they love HIMYM characters xD) in the last season. where marshall(occupation: therapist) looses his wife to an accident from a drunk brit and goes deep into a spiral of depression neglecting her 16(or 17) year old daughter, drowning into pills and alcohol and hookers. They all struggle to grieve the loss of her beautiful wife, marshal starts breaking therapist rules and starts experimenting with his clients to see some change in his life and feel better.
The cast is fantastic, each and every single one of the character is well-developed and experiences meaningful growth and change over time. now story writing is top notch here with a great mix of humor and heartfelt-drama with some excellent one liners, cunning jokes, running gags and meaningful thematic parallelism one amazing example of this comes in the episode &amp;rsquo;the drug wears off&amp;rsquo; in which actual drugs are compared to the drug which marhsall is using to numb himself from his loss very beautifully within the characters dialogue. there was not even a single character in this show that i would say is not needed and was extra(which netflix does very oftenly. each and every characters weighs in to the story even every single one of the marhsall friends&amp;rsquo; patients too. the writing style is very consistent, bright and vibrant among the episodes and the seasons consisting of a refreshing departure from darker tones to modern comedies. and somehow it&amp;rsquo;s very uplifting and fun to watch it certainly helped me unknowingly. the stories are compelling, with beautiful moments like the evolving father-daughter relationship and the vulnerability of Harrison Ford’s character as he deals with parkinson’s. The serious topics are handled with such care that they truly touch your heart. it definitely uses music to fire up neurons in your brain as for example i am obsessed with the strokes and i listen to them regularly, read their lyrics and all. and in one episode when they played &amp;lsquo;bad decisions&amp;rsquo; by them i was alr jumping due to the scene this score being played made that scene even more climatic. the scores are placed in the story very appropriately and are chosen very carefully so that they adds on the nature and the tone of the story going on. the location chosen is very pretty and the cinematography, color mixing in up to mark.
Well now every show is not perfect this one too, it somehow shows different ideologies which might not be coherent with everyone&amp;rsquo;s perspective, apple&amp;rsquo;s move to downgrade the family emoji to introducing pregnant men emojis kind of thing can be seen here. it’s not surprising that this ideology spills into their shows, often in ways that come across as heavy-handed. while the series has its entertaining aspects, you would encounter recurring themes such as: society admiring an 80-year-old woman’s beauty as though she is young, promoting cosmetic surgery among women as normal, portraying masculinity as inherently toxic, and the idea that being a man or being white is something to apologize for. but this is a fun blog these were my views on it and should not be taken to be grained in your head to form an opinion on such topic without even seeing it once.you might have different opinions on such topics and you&amp;rsquo;re free to stick on to them, experiment with them. not my business and neither should be anyone else&amp;rsquo;s opinions be yours that&amp;rsquo;s what some random chaiwala in the hills taught me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;popcorn-timeor-maybe-not&#34;&gt;Popcorn time(or maybe not)&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The ogs knows that any issue of this blog can&amp;rsquo;t go without a movie review and dw it won&amp;rsquo;t it&amp;rsquo;s just that this blog is going too big so i might only cover a single one for now and leave the other one for the next issue.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://qu-bit1.github.io/margaret.png&#34; alt=&#34;thesubstance&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Who doesn&amp;rsquo;t love horror films, and who doesn&amp;rsquo;t love pretty girls. mix them both and we get &amp;lsquo;The substance&amp;rsquo; so i watched this purely because i saw a single blood lust scene on reddit which was so good that it reminded me of bloodborne. so i plugged in and started watching it without any pre-context. and it was purely coincidental that i was alone that night(not usual ofc), the lights were off and clock showed 3 in the morning(ofc not usual for me). i cannot even count the number of times i gasped in between the film like real gasps, hands on head, covering mouth, eyes and what not. the ambience in this film is what really catches you in many different ways it&amp;rsquo;s ominous, disturbing and profoundly engaging. demi moore performs absolutely fantastic in every scene of the film that you can almost sense the heaviness of her character&amp;rsquo;s disintegrating mind. when you reach the part where you actually know what the &amp;lsquo;substance&amp;rsquo; is you&amp;rsquo;ll feel how the writer is portraying physical beauty to represent an artificial mask we put on to hide our insecurities, our real selves that society often chooses to ignore. it&amp;rsquo;s haunting yet captivating.
the visuals are stunning—dark hues with an almost dreamlike quality, which makes you question whether what you&amp;rsquo;re seeing is even real or a manifestation of the protagonist&amp;rsquo;s deteriorating mental state. There’s a consistent theme of identity and transformation, and it’s woven so tightly into the narrative that you feel like you’re being pulled along for the ride whether you want to or not. oh, and the body horror? perfectly executed. It’s not about cheap jump scares or gore for the sake of gore. it’s thoughtful, symbolic, and downright eerie.
Also, a side note the sound design here deserves its own shoutout. You could argue that sound is its own character in the movie—there&amp;rsquo;s this eerie synthwave undercurrent that reminded me of &lt;em&gt;Blade Runner&lt;/em&gt; mixed with &lt;em&gt;Hereditary&lt;/em&gt;&amp;rsquo;s creeping unease. If you watch this with good headphones or speakers, you’ll notice how each whisper, each creak, and each sharp note seems deliberately placed to keep your anxiety just a notch below full-blown panic.
But just like everything else, there are flaws. Some parts drag a bit—scenes that seem like they’re trying too hard to be “deep” rather than genuinely unsettling. And while the film’s commentary on beauty and societal pressure is clever, it sometimes feels like it’s spoon-feeding its message instead of letting you figure it out yourself.sStill, for any horror fan looking for something fresh, this one is worth the time, especially if you’re into psychologically charged horror that makes you reflect on the world and yourself a bit differently after watching.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Alright, enough rambling for one day. Conda’s probably done installing by now, and I need a cup of coffee to match this not so freezing weather. Till next time, keep experimenting with life (and maybe consider giving lossless audio another shot with a proper DAC setup—worth it, I swear xD).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;seriously tho hmu for music, art, film or anything you wanna talk about&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://matias.me/nsfw/&#34;&gt;byee xp&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Time</title>
      <link>https://qu-bit1.github.io/posts/time/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Jul 2024 04:35:48 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://qu-bit1.github.io/posts/time/</guid>
      <description>&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;music&#34;&gt;Music&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Recently, I have developed a fondness for jazz; it somehow makes me dance and feel superior. Other than that, my music taste has taken a very wide curve from indie rock to alt rock to raw rock. Now I&amp;rsquo;m stuck with April Rain and White Moth Black Butterfly (thanks Chucky xp). Seriously, go listen to them; you&amp;rsquo;ll appreciate each instrument being played in there and the harmony they meddle into.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <content>&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;music&#34;&gt;Music&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Recently, I have developed a fondness for jazz; it somehow makes me dance and feel superior. Other than that, my music taste has taken a very wide curve from indie rock to alt rock to raw rock. Now I&amp;rsquo;m stuck with April Rain and White Moth Black Butterfly (thanks Chucky xp). Seriously, go listen to them; you&amp;rsquo;ll appreciate each instrument being played in there and the harmony they meddle into.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;which-film-this-time&#34;&gt;Which Film This Time?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This summer, I took a course on &amp;lsquo;Introduction to Chinese Cinema&amp;rsquo; by Prof. Ritwij Bhowmik here at IITK. I have been analysing films from story, basic cinematography, and a cinematic audience perspective. If you feel something different from usual in this review than others, all thanks to him.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There&amp;rsquo;s this Wong Kar Wai collection always popping up on my Mubi feed for a long time, and yea, the thumbnails were really catchy, for instance &amp;lsquo;FALLEN ANGELS&amp;rsquo; RAHHHHHH.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;fallen.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;fallen angel&#34;&gt;
I really meant to give them a watch, and I&amp;rsquo;m glad I waited. After watching Farewell My Concubine and YiYi in ART707 classes, I experienced some sort of level up in film-watching capabilities. YiYi, directed by Edward Yang, is a film that truly reflects what an art film means. At first, I didn&amp;rsquo;t know what to expect when it came to cinematography and his unique style and approach when we started the film. This isn’t a film that you’re going to watch once and be done with. I, for sure, will be dwelling on it and its story for a long time, digesting what it means and reflecting it with my own life, and returning to rewatch the movie again and again. It’s totally worth it. But yea, this time it&amp;rsquo;s not YiYi which I&amp;rsquo;m gonna rant about. It&amp;rsquo;s Chungking Express.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the side note, watch &amp;lsquo;Perfect Days.&amp;rsquo; It&amp;rsquo;s about Hirayama. Who&amp;rsquo;s he, you may ask? He lives a beautiful life, spending his days balancing his job as a caretaker of Tokyo’s public toilets with his passion for music, literature, and photography. His structured routine (inspired me to fix my sleep schedule lol) is slowly interrupted by unexpected encounters that force him to reconnect with his past.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;chung-hing-sam-lamchungking-jungle-1994&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Chung Hing Sam Lam&lt;/em&gt; (&lt;em&gt;Chungking Jungle&lt;/em&gt;, 1994)&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;top-100-movies-1990s-chungkingexpress.webp&#34; alt=&#34;chungking-express&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For you to appreciate, I have attached some shots from the film.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(Suggestion - read this while listening to California Dreamin’ by The Mamas &amp;amp; the Papas)
Not gonna lie, when I first saw Wong Kar Wai&amp;rsquo;s photo, I thought, yess, this is the guy who makes classic triad or gangster movies. Although I was not wrong, what I saw truly tickled my brain. After watching Chungking Express, I was not sure I could capture Wong Kar Wai&amp;rsquo;s style and his artistic essence, so I watched &amp;lsquo;In the Mood for Love,&amp;rsquo; &amp;lsquo;Fallen Angels,&amp;rsquo; and &amp;lsquo;2046&amp;rsquo; too, so I can express my feelings about Chungking Express somewhat from the director&amp;rsquo;s perspective.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First of all, one interesting fact: the film was made in three months only, start to finish, and has a wacky spontaneity that is unique in his oeuvre. The film can be divided into two parts. The first half is a whiff to the gangster thriller; the second is pure electric romance. The narrative comprises two separate and distinctive stories as they have their own characters and locations. Although each section focuses on some lovesick cop who yearns for their ex-girlfriends until another woman captures their attention. The first part you&amp;rsquo;ll experience is classic every HK film has, a warren of flophouses, cut-rate shops, and dubious import-export ventures. This haven for criminals and the destitute from all corners of the globe proves to be a dead end for Wong, who abandons it a few minutes in pursuit of a more captivating romantic prospect.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-pineapple-cans&#34;&gt;The Pineapple Cans&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cop no. 223, our first protagonist, has been dumped by his girlfriend May on April Fool’s Day. He refuses to believe it, and so he buys a can of pineapple every day for the month because it’s her favorite thing to eat &amp;amp; specifically hunts down the perfect can, ones that expire exactly on May 1st. The pineapple cans and their impending expiration date take on a dreamlike quality. The overly sweet canned pineapple mirrors the cloying nature of his puppy love, and as May 1 nears, he unsuccessfully attempts to feed the pineapple syrup to his dog, symbolizing May&amp;rsquo;s lack of interest in his affections. Of course, that obsession with eating expired food does no good to anyone. The emotional pain turns to his physical discomfort. By vomiting, he purges the past and instantly becomes infatuated with the next woman he encounters.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While reading about it online, I found something very interesting and which fits with this so much. Wong Kar Wai was born in China but is a Hong Kong citizen. The film was released in 1994, just 3 years away from the handover of HK to China. The expiration date was a front for a deeper political meaning, that is, freedom that has an expiration date in the near future. This is what I love about movies from China, Taiwan, and HK, that they always play with their political expressions and convey it very artistically. Similarly, when the blonde wigged girl was slipped the sardines dated May 1, she gets the message that time is running out for her. If she doesn’t deliver the drugs that her two-timing couriers have stolen, she will die. Same thing, the expiration date, very beautiful depiction.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The CDs revolving in the bar are so satisfying to watch. Our cop and that blonde wigged woman literally collide into each other in the opening chase sequence, and naturally, our cop falls in love with a drug smuggler at a bar. She’s wearing a blonde wig, sunglasses that completely cover her face, and a beige trench-coat. We fall into the antics of their story, and then the part ends at a take-out restaurant (Midnight Express) around which the action of the second part revolves. It&amp;rsquo;s the place where our cop goes to call his answering machine. He has a very nice password - &amp;rsquo;love you for ten thousand years&amp;rsquo; - to find out if May called or not. The owner at the restaurant tries to fix him up with a &amp;lsquo;fake&amp;rsquo; May, one of his waitresses, and afterwards with Faye Wong, but he leaves and his part of the story is over.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;some-cinematic-elements&#34;&gt;Some Cinematic Elements&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;chungking-express-006.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;time&#34;&gt;
This is such a beautifully visual film. As Cop 223 moves through the night markets, everything blurs around him and is sped up while he’s sprinting through to capture the unknown assassin. It lends itself to the thought that he’s moving so quickly and across a vast distance, especially with the use of zooms and blur around him. The movie shows time, dates, and clocks very much, portraying that time stops for nothing. There are these moments of rushes throughout the film, where everything is moving so quickly except our main character. It adds a sense that time is ticking, where everyone around you is going places and has somewhere to be but you’re stuck here. The expiration dates of pineapples present one of his recurring notions through this scene, which is that change is inevitable and unavoidable. After the blonde woman comes into his life, it pauses completely, and only his narration continues, the one where he says he’s going to fall in love with her quite soon.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;california-dreamin&#34;&gt;California Dreamin&amp;rsquo;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The other protagonist, also a cop, cop no. 663, is someone who routinely stops by the Midnight Express to pick up a chef salad for his flight attendant girlfriend. The owner tries to sell him something other than a chef salad as he was fixated upon that and successfully sells him something else (I&amp;rsquo;m too lazy to remember what, maybe a hot dog?). A few days in, same as our first protagonist, his girlfriend leaves him. She comes to the restaurant to deliver a leaving note along with keys to his apartment, which, of course, the owner and people working there opened and read a lot of times xD. Faye tries to give him his letter, but he tries to run away from it every time. Now see, here&amp;rsquo;s the interesting part. During the intro scene of 663, the shot is ostensibly from Faye’s point of view, but as no. 663 walks into close-up, she’s not the only one instantly smitten by the most soulful set of peepers in contemporary cinema, so exhilarating.
663 is obsessed with his ex, has her stuffed animals (similar to pineapple cans) in his apartment, and then we see him occasionally playing with toy airplanes, soaps, etc. Faye starts using the keys his ex left and starts visiting his apartment when he changes from a night to day shift. She starts cleaning her house, changing his sheets, buying new house stuff, and food for him. That man was living off sardines, coffee, and some rice. Now that I say it, the film was full of food from start to end, cute. The cleaning of his house portrays clearing his mind in some sense. She keeps falling for him more and more. Faye has this obsession with California Dreamin&amp;rsquo; song. She wants to settle up in California, so you&amp;rsquo;ll hear the song throughout the second part. The use of the particular song symbolizes the westernization HK has experienced through the decades. One interesting thing - when she&amp;rsquo;s cleaning his apartment, she hears the Cantonese cover of the Cranberries’ “&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=TXceE8x-9GA&#34;&gt;Dreams&lt;/a&gt;” by a singer named &amp;lsquo;Faye Wong&amp;rsquo;. Never have I ever bopped so hard to an Asian&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;song other than this (of course, leaving Eve out of this). He’s so lost in his own head that he talks to a bar of soap to keep himself company. 663 is completely oblivious to Faye&amp;rsquo;s obvious interest in him and remains unaware that she has been subtly transforming his apartment. Due to an unexpected encounter at his front door, as she&amp;rsquo;s leaving and he&amp;rsquo;s arriving, Faye is thrown off balance, causing her to impulsively slam the door in his face. Lmao, this scene was actually so funny. Despite the complexities of their shared scenes, the undeniable chemistry between the two actors creates a palpable sense of attraction. Their love feels so innocent.
&lt;img src=&#34;faye.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;so romantic&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;some-more-cinematic-elements-hehe&#34;&gt;Some More Cinematic Elements Hehe&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I can never leave out cinematography in any film, right? Guess who was the cinematographer in this film? None other than Christopher Doyle, accompanied by Andrew Lau. The movie was mostly shot on a handheld camera, which perfectly fits the crowded and tense urban environment where the story takes place. It gives off a sense of claustrophobia reflecting the mental status of the characters. The first part is fast-paced, with the camera moving rapidly in the chaos of the city at night. Wong Kar Wai is well known for his use of colors, with films saturated in deep and meaningful tones, visual metaphors developed to emphasize the melodrama of the story. We can read into the narrative without relying on dialogue. In one of the scenes, without explicitly being told that the characters are facing separation, he very beautifully uses a deep blue along with the visual prop of a small airplane to suggest the characters won’t see each other for a long time after this encounter. The first part is filled with yellow color representing madness, changing into orange symbolizing optimism, and youthful connections. It is observable changing from yellow to orange.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The film uses so many cinematographic techniques like focus blur, freeze frames, zooms, blurred zooms, and tracking shots.
I cannot describe how beautiful these blurry shots can feel. It just fits in like a cog in the machine, so satisfying describing the psychology of the characters time to time, portraying time. You just have to go and see for yourself. After Chungking, I recommend Fallen Angels. It will feel like the third part of Chungking Express.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;im-a-cop.png&#34; alt=&#34;im-a-cop&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ok bye :)&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
