<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Books on don&#39;t panic</title>
    <link>https://qu-bit1.github.io/tags/books/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Books on don&#39;t panic</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 19 Jan 2024 03:50:43 +0530</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://qu-bit1.github.io/tags/books/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Renaissance</title>
      <link>https://qu-bit1.github.io/posts/renaissance/renaissance/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Jan 2024 03:50:43 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://qu-bit1.github.io/posts/renaissance/renaissance/</guid>
      <description>&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;hello hello, missed me? i forgot i had a blog so here i am back after 6 monthish maybe? although i didn&amp;rsquo;t posted much in the start&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;wannabe-artist&#34;&gt;wannabe artist&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;literature&#34;&gt;literature&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;i wanted to get into literature after the tech meet, so i started reading books again but this time no sci-fi, no biographies or anything only literature, so i read &amp;lsquo;&lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/A_Thousand_Splendid_Suns&#34;&gt;A thousand splendid suns&lt;/a&gt;&amp;rsquo; by Khaled Hosseini and i honestly liked it very much, it is a compelling but a heart-wrenching story of two women, both with distinct family background and about a generation apart, who were brought together under the same household through the tragic sweep of war. it is a story set between the period around the 1960s to 2000s in afghanistan; a period during the invasion by the soviet union and the rise of the dreadful taliban and i&amp;rsquo;d happily recommend this book to everyone.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <content>&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;hello hello, missed me? i forgot i had a blog so here i am back after 6 monthish maybe? although i didn&amp;rsquo;t posted much in the start&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;wannabe-artist&#34;&gt;wannabe artist&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;literature&#34;&gt;literature&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;i wanted to get into literature after the tech meet, so i started reading books again but this time no sci-fi, no biographies or anything only literature, so i read &amp;lsquo;&lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/A_Thousand_Splendid_Suns&#34;&gt;A thousand splendid suns&lt;/a&gt;&amp;rsquo; by Khaled Hosseini and i honestly liked it very much, it is a compelling but a heart-wrenching story of two women, both with distinct family background and about a generation apart, who were brought together under the same household through the tragic sweep of war. it is a story set between the period around the 1960s to 2000s in afghanistan; a period during the invasion by the soviet union and the rise of the dreadful taliban and i&amp;rsquo;d happily recommend this book to everyone.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;movies&#34;&gt;movies&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;i started watching movies again, started with &lt;strong&gt;borat&lt;/strong&gt; and it was awesome, the fact that people didn&amp;rsquo;t knew they were being filmed for a movie, which brought their true-self out was very intriguing concept. it features real-life interactions with americans in an unscripted way of borat interviewing and interacting with real-life Americans who believe he is a foreigner with little or no understanding of American customs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;i started my &lt;a href=&#34;https://mubi.com/en/in/showing&#34;&gt;mubi&lt;/a&gt; 3 month trial subscription, which according to the internet is &amp;lsquo;a curated streaming service, an ever-changing collection of hand-picked films. From new directors to award-winners. From everywhere on earth&amp;rsquo; and probably true, i partly watched a pakistani movie &amp;lsquo;joyland&amp;rsquo; and it had so good cinematography.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;so yea &lt;del&gt;naturally&lt;/del&gt;, the next movie i watched was &lt;strong&gt;the 400 blows&lt;/strong&gt; which was my first exposure to the french cinema and it was so nice that it encouraged me to write a movie review blog on which i did started working on but, realised that a blog specifically for movie reviews was not gonna cut it, &lt;em&gt;one time dopamine it is only&lt;/em&gt;(yoda said to me this in a dream), so i decided to just toture you all by just sharing my already written and &amp;lsquo;&lt;em&gt;well curated&lt;/em&gt;&amp;rsquo; review here and make the post very long :) ok but so the thing is, i did wrote a review of the movie although it has some trivial parts copied from the internet which i read but didn&amp;rsquo;t bothered &amp;lsquo;&lt;em&gt;paraphrasing&lt;/em&gt;&amp;rsquo; so the review below is almost 86% original i&amp;rsquo;d say. also i focused on the cinemat part majorly ig.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;i then watched &lt;strong&gt;dead poets society&lt;/strong&gt; and i&amp;rsquo;d say only one thing &amp;lsquo;&lt;em&gt;carpe diem&lt;/em&gt;&amp;rsquo;. i&amp;rsquo;m now gonna try poetry too :)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-400-blows&#34;&gt;THE 400 BLOWS&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;about&#34;&gt;About&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_400_Blows&#34;&gt;The 400 Blows&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; ( French: &lt;em&gt;Les quatre cents coups&lt;/em&gt;) is a 1959 French coming of age drama film clocking a total of 96 minutes. This movie was the debut of &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Fran%C3%A7ois_Truffaut&#34;&gt;François Truffaut&lt;/a&gt; as a director, (fun fact - his first non-french movie was the adaption of the classic science fiction novel &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Fahrenheit_451_%281966_film%29&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Fahrenheit 451&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, and was his only English-speaking film, filmed in England, was a great challenge for Truffaut, because he barely spoke English himself &amp;amp; this was also Truffaut&amp;rsquo;s first film in colour.)
The 400 Blows is a film about Antoine Doinel, an adolescent(probably) in Paris who is often misunderstood, and  struggles with his parents and teachers due to his rebellious behavior, defining the French New Wave movement, and has four sequels: &lt;em&gt;Antoine et Colette&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Stolen Kisses&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Bed and Board&lt;/em&gt;, and &lt;em&gt;Love on the Run&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I watched it on &lt;a href=&#34;https://mubi.com/en/in/films/the-400-blows&#34;&gt;Mubi&lt;/a&gt; but I think it&amp;rsquo;s also available on Prime Video. I recommend watching the film as the following is my review of how I perceived the film, I&amp;rsquo;ll be mostly talking about cinematography of the film as I found it really good among the standards that were set during that time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;plot&#34;&gt;Plot&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The movie is set in Paris and seeing the French culture in the 1950s was quite mesmerising experience for me. People walking down in their coats and beautiful attire really helps to capture the liveliness of Paris during the 1950s for the viewer’s through its detailed and elaborate visualization of Paris’ architecture, buildings, bustling streets, etc.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Antoine Doinel lives with his mother and stepfather in a tiny little apartment, they are poor and his parents are generally inattentive. The school makes his life more miserable and unbearable than at home thanks to his ruthless teacher who is a total nightmare, grabbing students by neck, throwing them out of class, shouting, taunting them. His only escape from the shackles of everyday life is to bunk off school with his one friend, going to cinema, smoking cigars, exploring the city of Paris.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Antoine Doinel lives in a tiny flat with his mother and stepfather, who are poor and generally inattentive. A ruthlessly domineering teacher makes life at school more unbearable than at home. His only escape from the shackles of everyday life is to bunk off school with his one friend, go to the fairground, or visit the cinema. His problems deepen as frustration, desperation, and loneliness lead to his expulsion from school and subsequent running away from home.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The one scene where he rides that somewhat advanced merry-go-round, signifies something interesting which i dont have the energy to explain, so go see it for yourself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;cinematography&#34;&gt;Cinematography&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One thing that strike out to me was the cinematography of this film as in the camera movements felt &lt;del&gt;odd&lt;/del&gt; and circular as if I am looking at the film through the eyes of a fish when the camera moves, at certain moments, after a bit of research(wikipedia :) ) I came to know that it shot in the &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Anamorphic_format&#34; title=&#34;Anamorphic format&#34;&gt;anamorphic format&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/List_of_anamorphic_format_trade_names&#34; title=&#34;List of anamorphic format trade names&#34;&gt;DyaliScope&lt;/a&gt; .&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The movie starts on a travelling shot down in the streets of Paris, carefully blending The Eiffel Tower in the distance ensuring that my attention is naturally drawn to it throughout the opening sequence. The camera moves and cuts to a new tracking shot bringing the Eiffel Tower slightly closer each time. Keeping it the centre of attention the camera runs parallel. in circular motion around it(trust me bro, just see it, it&amp;rsquo;s beautiful). The most beautiful thing about this shot is that it can be seen as the POV of a child riding a car around Paris whose attention is always fixated on the Tower which is just there, just like we used to see the moon in night while travelling when we used to be small.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is one notable instance throughout the film which uses the newfound technique of the long take; a shot that films a scene for a long period of time .
The film uses the &amp;rsquo;long take technique&amp;rsquo; in the film which was newly found around that time which is a shot that is films a scene for a long period of time usually accompanied with the camera panning from a higher location (not necessarily though). This technique can be observed in one scene, as the teacher and the boys run through the streets of Paris, the camera pans from a higher, wider view, and captures the Paris cityscape of the time as the boys sneakily run away from the group into buildings and alleyways. This allows the film to direct the viewer’s attentions towards significant narrative elements. In this case, this technique really helps to capture the liveliness of Paris during the 1950s for the viewer’s through its detailed and elaborate visualization of Paris’  buildings, bustling streets, etc. Ultimately capturing the liveliness of the city.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I really like that the camera movements are motivated by actions for example the camera acts as a quick pan to the teacher imitating the sudden movement of the eyes. The camera pans as it follows our main character, and it even pans back at the teacher after Antoine shakes his fist at the guys who got him caught. Think for a moment why that pan happened? If you remember your school days and you were doing something like passing &amp;lsquo;grass&amp;rsquo; - you never wanted to get caught and you&amp;rsquo;d always look at the teacher, to see if they&amp;rsquo;re looking. The camera pan is acting as your eyes. So after the shaken fist , you&amp;rsquo;d look at the teacher to see if he noticed it because you wouldn&amp;rsquo;t want to get caught.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;if you are &amp;lsquo;vela&amp;rsquo; enough that you reached this line, remind me to keep this blog alive or criticise me (i take constructive criticism very seriously :hides-my-knife-smirkingly: )&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ok bye :)&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
