<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on don&#39;t panic</title>
    <link>https://qu-bit1.github.io/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on don&#39;t panic</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 09 Jul 2024 04:35:48 +0530</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://qu-bit1.github.io/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Time</title>
      <link>https://qu-bit1.github.io/posts/time/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Jul 2024 04:35:48 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://qu-bit1.github.io/posts/time/</guid>
      <description>music recently i have developed a fondness for jazz, it somehow makes me dance and feel superior. other than that my music taste has taken a very wide curve from indie rock to alt rock to raw rock, now im stuck with april rain, white moth black butterfly(thanks chuckky xp). seriously go listen to them, you&amp;rsquo;ll appreciate each instrument being played in there and the harmony they meddle into.</description>
      <content>&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;music&#34;&gt;music&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;recently i have developed a fondness for jazz, it somehow makes me dance and feel superior. other than that my music taste has taken a very wide curve from indie rock to alt rock to raw rock, now im stuck with april rain, white moth black butterfly(thanks chuckky xp). seriously go listen to them, you&amp;rsquo;ll appreciate each instrument being played in there and the harmony they meddle into.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;which-film-this-time&#34;&gt;which film this time?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;this summers i took a course on &amp;lsquo;introduction to chinese cinema&amp;rsquo; by Prof. Ritwij Bhowmik here at IITK. i have been analysing films from story, basic cinematography and a cinematic audience perspective. if you feel something different from usual in this review than others all thanks to him(and yea this is not a propoganda, i genuinely appreciate him and want to share how to appreciate the artistic expression in films)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;there&amp;rsquo;s this wong kar wai collection always popping up on my mubi feed from a long time and yea the thumbnails were really catchy for instance &amp;lsquo;FALLEN ANGELS&amp;rsquo; RAHHHHHH.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;fallen angel&#34; src=&#34;fallen.jpg&#34;&gt;
i really meant to give them a watch &amp;amp; im glad i waited after watching farewell my concubine and yiyi in ART707 classes, i experienced some sort of level up in film watching capabilities. YiYi directed by Edward Yang is a film which truly reflects what an art film means at first i didn&amp;rsquo;t knew what to expect when it came to cinematography and his unique style and approach when we started the film. this ain’t a film that you’re going to watch once and be done with it. i for sure will be dwelling on it and its story for a long time, digesting what it means and reflect it with my own life, and returning to rewatch the movie again and again. it’s totally worth it. but yea this time it&amp;rsquo;s not yiyi which im gonna rant about. it&amp;rsquo;s chungking express.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;on the side note watch &amp;lsquo;Perfect Days&amp;rsquo; it&amp;rsquo;s about Hirayama who&amp;rsquo;s he you may ask, he lives a beautiful life, spending his days balancing his job as a caretaker of tokyo’s public toilets with his passion for music, literature, and photography. his structured routine(inspired me to fix my sleep schedule lol) is slowly interrupted by unexpected encounters that force him to reconnect with his past.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;_chung-hing-sam-lam__chungking-jungle_-1994&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Chung hing sam lam&lt;/em&gt; (&lt;em&gt;Chungking Jungle&lt;/em&gt;, 1994)&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;chungking-express&#34; src=&#34;top-100-movies-1990s-chungkingexpress.webp&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For you to appreciate i have attached some shots from the film.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(suggestion - read this while listening to California Dreamin’ by The Mamas &amp;amp; the Papas)
not gonna lie when i first saw wong kar wai&amp;rsquo;s photo i thought yess this is the guy who makes classic triad or gangster movies. although i was not wrong but what i saw truly tickled my brain. after watching chungking express i was not sure i can capture wong kar wai&amp;rsquo;s style and his artistic essence so i watched &amp;lsquo;in the mood for love&amp;rsquo;, &amp;lsquo;fallen angels&amp;rsquo; &amp;amp; &amp;lsquo;2046&amp;rsquo; too, so i can express my feelings about chungking express somewhat from the director&amp;rsquo;s perspective.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;first of all one interesting fact the film was made in three months only, start to finish &amp;amp; has a wacky spontaneity that is unique in his oeuvre. the film can be divided in two parts the first half is a whiff to the gangster thriller, the second is pure electric romance. the narrative comprises two seperate and distinctive stories as they have their own characters and locations although each section focuses on some lovesick cop who yearns for their ex-girlfriends until another woman captures their attention. the first part you&amp;rsquo;ll experience classic every HK film have, a warren of flophouses, cut-rate shops, and dubious import-export ventures. this haven for criminals and the destitute from all corners of the globe proves to be a dead end for Wong who abandons down few minutes in pursuit of a more captivating romantic prospect.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-pineapple-cans&#34;&gt;the pineapple cans&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;cop no. 223 our first protagonist who has been dumped by his girlfriend May on april Fool’s Day. he refuses to believe it, and, so, he buys a can of pineapple every day for the month because it’s her favorite thing to eat &amp;amp; specifically hunts down the perfect can,ones that expire exactly on May 1st. the pineapple cans and their impending expiration date take on a dreamlike quality, the overly sweet canned pineapple mirrors the cloying nature of his puppy love and as May 1 nears, he unsuccessfully attempts to feed the pineapple syrup to his dog, symbolizing May&amp;rsquo;s lack of interest in his affections and ofc that obsession with eating expiry food does no good to anyone, the emotional pain turn to his physical discomfort, by vomiting he purges the past and instantly becomes infatuated with the next woman he encounters.
while reading about it online i found something very interesting and which fits with this so much, wong kar wai was born in china but is a hong kong citizen. the film was released in 1994 just 3 years away from the handover of HK to china, the expiration date was a front for a deeper political meaning that is freedom that has an expiration date in the near future. this is what i love about movies from china, taiwan and HK that they always play with their political expressions and convey it very artistically. similarly when the blonde wigged girl was slipped the sardines dated may 1 she gets the message that time is running out for her, if she doesn’t deliver the drugs that her two-timing couriers have stolen, she will die same thing the expiration date, very beautiful depiction.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;the CDs revolving in the bar are so satisfying to watch. our cop and that blonde wigged literally collide into each other in the opening chase sequence and naturally our cop falls in love with a drug smuggler at a bar. she’s wearing a blonde wig, sunglasses that completely cover her face, and a beige trench-coat. we fall into the antics of their story, and then the part ends at a take-out restaurant(midnight express) around which the action of the second part revolves. its the place where our cop goes to call is his answering machine, he has a very nice password - &amp;rsquo;love you for ten thousand years&amp;rsquo; to find out if May called or not. the owner at the restaurant tries to fix him up with a &amp;lsquo;fake&amp;rsquo; May one of his waitresses, and afterwards with Faye Wong but he leaves and his part of the story is over&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;some-cinematic-elements&#34;&gt;some cinematic elements&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;time&#34; src=&#34;chungking-express-006.jpg&#34;&gt;
this is such a beautifully visual film, as Cop 223 moves through the night markets, everything blurs around him and is sped up, while he’s sprinting through to capture the unknown assassin. It lends itself to the thought that he’s moving so quickly and across a vast distance, especially with the use of zooms and blur around him. the movie shows time, dates, clocks very much portraying time stops for nothing there are these moments of rushes throughout the film, where everything is moving so quickly except our main character it adds a sense of time is ticking, where everyone around you is going places and has somewhere to be but you’re stuck here, the expiration dates of pineapples presents one of his recurring notions through this scene, which is that change is inevitable and unavoidable. after the blonde woman comes into his life it pauses completely and only his narration continues, the one where he says he’s going to fall in love with her quite soon.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;california-dreamin&#34;&gt;california dreamin&amp;rsquo;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;the other protagonist also a cop, cop no. 663 is someone who routinely stops by the midnight express to pick up a chef salad for his flight attendant girlfriend. the owner tries to sell him something other than chef salad as he was fixated upon that and successfully sells him something else(im too lazy to remember what, maybe a hot dog?). few days in, same as our first protagonist his girlfriend leaves him, she comes to the restaurant to deliver a leaving note along with keys to his apartment which ofc the owner and people working their opened and read a lot of times xD. Faye tries to give him his letter but he tries to run away from it everytime. now see here&amp;rsquo;s the interesting part during the intro scene of 663 the shot is ostensibly from Faye’s point of view, but as no. 663 walks into close-up, she’s not the only one instantly smitten by the most soulful set of peepers in contemporary cinema, so exhilarating.
663 is obsessed with his ex, has her stuffed animals(similar to pineapple cans) in his apartment, and then we see him occasionally playing with toy airplanes, soaps etc. faye starts using his the keys his ex left and start visiting his apartment when he changes from a night to day shift. she starts cleaning her house, changing his sheets, buying new housestuff, food for him that man was living off on sardines, coffee and some rice. now that i say it, the film was full of food from starting to the end, cute. the cleaning of his house portrays clearing his mind in some sense, she keeps falling for him more and more. faye has this obsession with california dreamin&amp;rsquo; song, she wants to settle up in california, so you&amp;rsquo;ll hear the song throughout the second part, the use of the particular song symbolizes the westernization HK has experienced through the decades. one interesting thing - when she&amp;rsquo;s cleaning his apartment she hears to the cantonese cover of the cranberries’ “&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=TXceE8x-9GA&#34;&gt;Dreams&lt;/a&gt;” by a singer named &amp;lsquo;Faye Wong&amp;rsquo;, never have i ever bopped so hard to an asian song other than this(ofc leaving eve out of this). he’s so lost in his own head that he talks to a bar of soap to keep himself company. 663 is completely oblivious to Faye&amp;rsquo;s obvious interest in him, and remains unaware that she has been subtly transforming his apartment. due to an unexpected encounter at his front door, as she&amp;rsquo;s leaving and he&amp;rsquo;s arriving, throws Faye off balance, causing her to impulsively slam the door in his face lmaoo this scene was actually so funny. despite the complexities of their shared scenes, the undeniable chemistry between the two actors creates a palpable sense of attraction. their love feels so innocent.
&lt;img alt=&#34;so romantic&#34; src=&#34;faye.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;some-more-cinematic-elements-hehe&#34;&gt;some more cinematic elements hehe&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;i can never leave out cinematography in any film right? guess who was the cinematographer in this film, none other than Christopher Doyle accompanied by Andrew Lau. the movie was mostly shot on a handheld camera which perfectly fits the crowded and tense urban environment where the story takes place. it gives off a sense of claustrophobia reflecting the mental status of the characters. the first part is fast paced with the camera moving rapidly in the chaos of the city in the night. wong kar wai is well known for his use of colors, with films saturated in deep and meaningful tones, visual metaphors developed to emphasise the melodrama of the story, we can read into the narrative without relying on dialogue. in one of the scenes without explicitly being told that the characters are facing separation, he very beautifully uses a deep blue along with the visual prop of a small aeroplane to suggest the characters won’t see each other for a long time after this encounter. the first part is filled with yellow color representing madness, changing into orange symbolising optimism, youthful connections, and it is observable changing from yellow to orange.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;the film uses so many cinematographic techniques like focus blur, freeze frames, zooms, blurred zooms, tracking shots.
I cannot describe how beautiful this blurry shots can feel, it just fits in like a cog in the machine, so satisfying describing the psychology of the characters time to time, portraying time. you just have to go and see for yourself. after chungking i recommend fallen angels, it will feel like the third part of chungking express.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;im-a-cop&#34; src=&#34;im-a-cop.png&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Renaissance</title>
      <link>https://qu-bit1.github.io/posts/renaissance/renaissance/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Jan 2024 03:50:43 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://qu-bit1.github.io/posts/renaissance/renaissance/</guid>
      <description>hello hello, missed me? i forgot i had a blog so here i am back after 6 monthish maybe? although i didn&amp;rsquo;t posted much in the start
wannabe artist literature i wanted to get into literature after the tech meet, so i started reading books again but this time no sci-fi, no biographies or anything only literature, so i read &amp;lsquo;A thousand splendid suns&amp;rsquo; by Khaled Hosseini and i honestly liked it very much, it is a compelling but a heart-wrenching story of two women, both with distinct family background and about a generation apart, who were brought together under the same household through the tragic sweep of war.</description>
      <content>&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;hello hello, missed me? i forgot i had a blog so here i am back after 6 monthish maybe? although i didn&amp;rsquo;t posted much in the start&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;wannabe-artist&#34;&gt;wannabe artist&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;literature&#34;&gt;literature&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;i wanted to get into literature after the tech meet, so i started reading books again but this time no sci-fi, no biographies or anything only literature, so i read &amp;lsquo;&lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/A_Thousand_Splendid_Suns&#34;&gt;A thousand splendid suns&lt;/a&gt;&amp;rsquo; by Khaled Hosseini and i honestly liked it very much, it is a compelling but a heart-wrenching story of two women, both with distinct family background and about a generation apart, who were brought together under the same household through the tragic sweep of war. it is a story set between the period around the 1960s to 2000s in afghanistan; a period during the invasion by the soviet union and the rise of the dreadful taliban and i&amp;rsquo;d happily recommend this book to everyone.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;movies&#34;&gt;movies&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;i started watching movies again, started with &lt;strong&gt;borat&lt;/strong&gt; and it was awesome, the fact that people didn&amp;rsquo;t knew they were being filmed for a movie, which brought their true-self out was very intriguing concept. it features real-life interactions with americans in an unscripted way of borat interviewing and interacting with real-life Americans who believe he is a foreigner with little or no understanding of American customs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;i started my &lt;a href=&#34;https://mubi.com/en/in/showing&#34;&gt;mubi&lt;/a&gt; 3 month trial subscription, which according to the internet is &amp;lsquo;a curated streaming service, an ever-changing collection of hand-picked films. From new directors to award-winners. From everywhere on earth&amp;rsquo; and probably true, i partly watched a pakistani movie &amp;lsquo;joyland&amp;rsquo; and it had so good cinematography.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;so yea &lt;del&gt;naturally&lt;/del&gt;, the next movie i watched was &lt;strong&gt;the 400 blows&lt;/strong&gt; which was my first exposure to the french cinema and it was so nice that it encouraged me to write a movie review blog on which i did started working on but, realised that a blog specifically for movie reviews was not gonna cut it, &lt;em&gt;one time dopamine it is only&lt;/em&gt;(yoda said to me this in a dream), so i decided to just toture you all by just sharing my already written and &amp;lsquo;&lt;em&gt;well curated&lt;/em&gt;&amp;rsquo; review here and make the post very long :) ok but so the thing is, i did wrote a review of the movie although it has some trivial parts copied from the internet which i read but didn&amp;rsquo;t bothered &amp;lsquo;&lt;em&gt;paraphrasing&lt;/em&gt;&amp;rsquo; so the review below is almost 86% original i&amp;rsquo;d say. also i focused on the cinemat part majorly ig.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;i then watched &lt;strong&gt;dead poets society&lt;/strong&gt; and i&amp;rsquo;d say only one thing &amp;lsquo;&lt;em&gt;carpe diem&lt;/em&gt;&amp;rsquo;. i&amp;rsquo;m now gonna try poetry too :)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-400-blows&#34;&gt;THE 400 BLOWS&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;about&#34;&gt;About&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_400_Blows&#34;&gt;The 400 Blows&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; ( French: &lt;em&gt;Les quatre cents coups&lt;/em&gt;) is a 1959 French coming of age drama film clocking a total of 96 minutes. This movie was the debut of &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Fran%C3%A7ois_Truffaut&#34;&gt;François Truffaut&lt;/a&gt; as a director, (fun fact - his first non-french movie was the adaption of the classic science fiction novel &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Fahrenheit_451_(1966_film)&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Fahrenheit 451&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, and was his only English-speaking film, filmed in England, was a great challenge for Truffaut, because he barely spoke English himself &amp;amp; this was also Truffaut&amp;rsquo;s first film in colour.)
The 400 Blows is a film about Antoine Doinel, an adolescent(probably) in Paris who is often misunderstood, and  struggles with his parents and teachers due to his rebellious behavior, defining the French New Wave movement, and has four sequels: &lt;em&gt;Antoine et Colette&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Stolen Kisses&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Bed and Board&lt;/em&gt;, and &lt;em&gt;Love on the Run&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I watched it on &lt;a href=&#34;https://mubi.com/en/in/films/the-400-blows&#34;&gt;Mubi&lt;/a&gt; but I think it&amp;rsquo;s also available on Prime Video. I recommend watching the film as the following is my review of how I perceived the film, I&amp;rsquo;ll be mostly talking about cinematography of the film as I found it really good among the standards that were set during that time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;plot&#34;&gt;Plot&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The movie is set in Paris and seeing the French culture in the 1950s was quite mesmerising experience for me. People walking down in their coats and beautiful attire really helps to capture the liveliness of Paris during the 1950s for the viewer’s through its detailed and elaborate visualization of Paris’ architecture, buildings, bustling streets, etc.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Antoine Doinel lives with his mother and stepfather in a tiny little apartment, they are poor and his parents are generally inattentive. The school makes his life more miserable and unbearable than at home thanks to his ruthless teacher who is a total nightmare, grabbing students by neck, throwing them out of class, shouting, taunting them. His only escape from the shackles of everyday life is to bunk off school with his one friend, going to cinema, smoking cigars, exploring the city of Paris.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Antoine Doinel lives in a tiny flat with his mother and stepfather, who are poor and generally inattentive. A ruthlessly domineering teacher makes life at school more unbearable than at home. His only escape from the shackles of everyday life is to bunk off school with his one friend, go to the fairground, or visit the cinema. His problems deepen as frustration, desperation, and loneliness lead to his expulsion from school and subsequent running away from home.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The one scene where he rides that somewhat advanced merry-go-round, signifies something interesting which i dont have the energy to explain, so go see it for yourself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;cinematography&#34;&gt;Cinematography&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One thing that strike out to me was the cinematography of this film as in the camera movements felt &lt;del&gt;odd&lt;/del&gt; and circular as if I am looking at the film through the eyes of a fish when the camera moves, at certain moments, after a bit of research(wikipedia :) ) I came to know that it shot in the &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Anamorphic_format&#34; title=&#34;Anamorphic format&#34;&gt;anamorphic format&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/List_of_anamorphic_format_trade_names&#34; title=&#34;List of anamorphic format trade names&#34;&gt;DyaliScope&lt;/a&gt; .&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The movie starts on a travelling shot down in the streets of Paris, carefully blending The Eiffel Tower in the distance ensuring that my attention is naturally drawn to it throughout the opening sequence. The camera moves and cuts to a new tracking shot bringing the Eiffel Tower slightly closer each time. Keeping it the centre of attention the camera runs parallel. in circular motion around it(trust me bro, just see it, it&amp;rsquo;s beautiful). The most beautiful thing about this shot is that it can be seen as the POV of a child riding a car around Paris whose attention is always fixated on the Tower which is just there, just like we used to see the moon in night while travelling when we used to be small.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is one notable instance throughout the film which uses the newfound technique of the long take; a shot that films a scene for a long period of time .
The film uses the &amp;rsquo;long take technique&amp;rsquo; in the film which was newly found around that time which is a shot that is films a scene for a long period of time usually accompanied with the camera panning from a higher location (not necessarily though). This technique can be observed in one scene, as the teacher and the boys run through the streets of Paris, the camera pans from a higher, wider view, and captures the Paris cityscape of the time as the boys sneakily run away from the group into buildings and alleyways. This allows the film to direct the viewer’s attentions towards significant narrative elements. In this case, this technique really helps to capture the liveliness of Paris during the 1950s for the viewer’s through its detailed and elaborate visualization of Paris’  buildings, bustling streets, etc. Ultimately capturing the liveliness of the city.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I really like that the camera movements are motivated by actions for example the camera acts as a quick pan to the teacher imitating the sudden movement of the eyes. The camera pans as it follows our main character, and it even pans back at the teacher after Antoine shakes his fist at the guys who got him caught. Think for a moment why that pan happened? If you remember your school days and you were doing something like passing &amp;lsquo;grass&amp;rsquo; - you never wanted to get caught and you&amp;rsquo;d always look at the teacher, to see if they&amp;rsquo;re looking. The camera pan is acting as your eyes. So after the shaken fist , you&amp;rsquo;d look at the teacher to see if he noticed it because you wouldn&amp;rsquo;t want to get caught.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;if you are &amp;lsquo;vela&amp;rsquo; enough that you reached this line, remind me to keep this blog alive or criticise me (i take constructive criticism very seriously :hides-my-knife-smirkingly: )&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ok bye :)&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Coffee</title>
      <link>https://qu-bit1.github.io/posts/coffee/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Aug 2023 15:30:52 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://qu-bit1.github.io/posts/coffee/</guid>
      <description>everyone knows i adore good coffee but this is not about coffee(would turn into a coffee blog in future maybe)
starting today you&amp;rsquo;ll hear my adventures not on a regular basis but yea i&amp;rsquo;ll rant once in a while, maybe this blog will die, who knows. writing this markdown in vim (now admit that i&amp;rsquo;m cool) and the theme somewhat resembles a terminal. istg i tried manipulating the css and i&amp;rsquo;ll not edit it further like it or not, i first wanted it to be a simple html page, but imposter syndrome kicked in(not gonna elaborate)</description>
      <content>&lt;h3 id=&#34;everyone-knows-i-adore-good-coffee&#34;&gt;everyone knows i adore good coffee&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;but this is not about coffee(would turn into a coffee blog in future maybe)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;starting today you&amp;rsquo;ll hear my adventures &lt;strong&gt;not on a regular basis&lt;/strong&gt; but yea i&amp;rsquo;ll rant once in a while, maybe this blog will die, who knows. writing this markdown in &lt;em&gt;vim&lt;/em&gt; (now admit that i&amp;rsquo;m cool) and the theme somewhat resembles a terminal. istg i tried manipulating the css and i&amp;rsquo;ll not edit it further like it or not, i first wanted it to be a simple html page, but imposter syndrome kicked in(not gonna elaborate)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ok bye&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
